- Will you ask if Francis
will not agree to t marriage
of Elizabeth to his son?
- It might be better for us
to pursue an alliance
with the Emperor.
- That would suit Katherine.
- Leave the greater things
to my care.
- Anyone can see that the King
is not so much in love with her
as he used to be. What's wrong?
- I don't know.
Perhaps she's afraid.
- So long as they are both
alive, I can't be safe.
I can just order their deaths!
[Maniacal laugh]
- You're crazy! Stop it!
You're the Queen of England.
Act like it!
- From now on, we must all
be careful not to lose
the King's love,
or everything is lost.
- Sir John, you have
an unexpected guest.
- Your Majesty, may I present
my daughter, Lady Jane Seymour?
- The hours of my death
draws fast on,
and I commend unto you
our daughter Mary.
beseeching you to be
a good father.
- Now I'm indeed Queen.
- The King of England has been
carried far from the shore,
but he does not know it.
He thinks he can swim alone.
Very soon, he will realize
he is not swimming,
but drowning.
- Have you told her about me?
- No.
- Why the hell not?!
- If you could read Greek, you
would know that even the gods
had problems with their wives.
- You are determined to close
every religious house
in England.
You are far too high-handed,
Mr. Cromwell.
You ought to be careful,
or I will have you cropped
at the neck.
- I did not bring you up
to quarrel with those
closest to the Crown.
- I am the King's wife.
- And you should remember
how you got there!
- He fell in love with me.
He respected me.
- Your daughter Jane should come
to court as Lady to Her Majesty.
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
- I am carrying the King's son.
- We are on the edge
of a golden world!